Arthur J. Finkelstein Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
Arthur J. Finkelstein Papers 1960-2019 1970-1989
MSS86414
Finkelstein, Arthur J.
49,500 items
139 containers plus 5 oversize
56.6 linear feet
187 digital files (3.43 GB)
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Republican pollster and political consultant. Correspondence, polls, clippings, memoranda, travel books, calendars, and other papers relating to Finkelstein's career as a Republican consultant and campaign manager.
Acquisition Information
The papers of Arthur J. Finkelstein were given to the Library by his husband, Donald Curiale, in 2021.
Transfers
Audio and video cassettes have been transferred to the Motion Picture, Broadcasting, and Recorded Sound Division where they are identified as part of the Arthur J. Finkelstein Papers. Patrons are encouraged to contact the Motion Picture, Broadcasting, and Recorded Sound Division in advance of a research visit.
Access and Restrictions
The papers of Arthur J. Finkelstein are open to research. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use. Access to digital content is available onsite only in the Manuscript Reading Room and requires advanced notice. Researchers are advised to contact the Manuscript Reading Room prior to visiting.
Technical Requirements
Digital files were created mostly in a Windows operating system, version unknown. Files include .vob, WordPerfect, Microsoft Word, Plain text, .zip, and unidentified text and database files.
Biographical Note
Date Event
1945, May 18 Born, Brooklyn, New York City, N.Y.
1967 B.A., Queens College, Queens, New York, N.Y.
1968-1970 Pollster and computer analyst, NBC News, New York, N.Y.
1969-1970 Computer programmer, New York Stock Exchange, New York, N.Y.
1970 Consultant, James L. Buckley United States Senate campaign, N.Y.
1972 Director of demographics and election analysis, Richard M. Nixon, presidential campaign
1972 Founder, AJF & Associates
1980-1993 Board member, Consumer Alert
2005 Married Donald Curiale
2013 Inducted, American Association of Political Consultants Hall of Fame
2017, Aug. 18 Died, Ipswich, Mass.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of Arthur J. Finkelstein span the years 1960-2019, with the bulk of the material dating from 1970 to 1989. The collection documents Finkelstein's work as a pollster and Republican political consultant. The papers are arranged into five series: Consultant File, Alphabetical File, Travel and Itineraries File, Personal File and Oversize.
After founding his political consulting company AJF & Associates, Finkelstein played a major part in the wave of Republican victories and the rise of the New Right during the 1970s and 1980s. The collection focuses almost entirely on his professional career and highlights the evolution of campaigns, fundraising, and messaging in this era. The Consultant File in particular demonstrates these changes as it showcases Finkelstein’s hands-on role as a campaign manager or consultant for a number of races. However, as Finkelstein’s involvement varied from race to race, not every campaign has extensive documentation.
The collection’s series are listed and briefly described below. A fuller description of each series and a list of its contents can be accessed in the series descriptions within the container list.
The Consultant File documents the mostly political work of Arthur J. Finkelstein, containing memoranda, polls, and other material related to various campaigns or organizations.
The Alphabetical File contains a mix of Finkelstein's working files, correspondence, and a variety of topics primarily concerned with Finkelstein's professional life.
The Travel and Itineraries File contains Finkelstein's scheduling books, detailing trips and meetings.
The Personal File contains a small collection of various material concerning Finkelstein's college years and family.
Oversize contains Rolodex cards, a scrapbook page, and a campaign poster.
Arrangement of the Collection
This collection is arranged in five series:
Consultant File, 1970-2015
Alphabetical File, 1970-2019
Travel and Itineraries File, 1983-2016
Personal File, 1960-2013
Oversize, 1970-1986
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Buckley, James Lane, 1923-; D'Amato, Alfonse.; Dolan, John T. (John Terry)--Correspondence.; Ferdinand, Joan--Correspondence.; Finkelstein family.; Finkelstein, Arthur J. (Arthur Jay), 1945-2017.; Helms, Jesse.; Kirkpatrick, Jeane J.--Correspondence.; Koehler, Judy, 1941-; Lauder, Ronald S.; Mack, Connie, III, 1940-; Netanyahu, Binyamin.; Nicholls, Gerald William James, 1958- --Correspondence.; Nickles, Don.; Sharon, Ariel.; Smith, Denny, 1938-; Stone, Roger, 1952- --Correspondence.
Organizations
AJF & Associates.; American Conservative Union.; Consumer Alert.; Likud (Political party: Israel); National Citizens' Coalition (Canada); National Congressional Club.; National Conservative Political Action Committee.; Republican Party (U.S.: 1854- ); United States. Congress--Elections.
Subjects
Advertising campaigns.; Advertising, Direct-mail.; Campaign funds.; Conservatism--United States.; Consulting firms--United States.; Elections--United States.; Elections.; Libertarianism--United States.; Political action committees--United States.; Political campaigns--United States.; Political campaigns.; Political candidates--United States.; Political candidates.; Political parties--Canada.; Political parties--Israel.; Political parties--United States.; Politics, Practical.; Radio advertising.; Republicanism--United States.; Telephone selling.; Television advertising.; Women political candidates.
Places
Long Island (N.Y.)--Politics and government.; New York (State)--Politics and government.; United States--Politics and government--20th century.; United States--Politics and government--21st century.
Occupations
Political consultants.; Pollsters.
Container List
- Consultant File, 1970-2015 (Box 1-62)
  The Consultant File documents the mostly political work of Arthur J. Finkelstein, containing memorandum, polls, and other material related to various campaigns or organizations. Specifically, the series contains material primarily from AJF & Associates, the polling and consulting company founded by Finkelstein. The firm specialized in political consulting for Republican candidates, and Finkelstein’s polling, coupled with direct mail for campaign fundraising and the use of independent expenditures, helped lead to a wave of Republican victories in the 1980s. The work for these campaigns could range from a simple poll to complete campaign management, where Finkelstein consulted on the crafting of oft-negative television and radio advertisements, direct mail letters, and other general advisement. Consequently, the amount of material in this series can vary from client to client. Some of the most noteworthy clients represented in this series are: James Lane Buckley, Alphonse D’Amato, Jesse Helms, Judy Koehler, Ronald S. Lauder, Don Nickles, Connie Mack III, and Denny Smith. Alongside individual candidates, Finkelstein played important roles in political action committees, such as the National Conservative Political Action Committee and the National Congressional Club. Later in his career, he helped consult for campaigns overseas, the most notable featured in this series being the National Citizen’s Coalition in Canada and the Likud party in Israel, where he managed the campaigns for Prime Ministers Benjamin Netanyahu and Ariel Sharon. Also represented in this series is the influence Finkelstein exercised in shaping state politics in New York, specifically in Long Island.
  Material types include correspondence, memoranda, polls, notes, and news clippings.
  Arranged alphabetically by name of political candidate or client. The file structure of the digital content maintained as received.
  - Acampora, Henrietta (Town supervisor, Brookhaven, N.Y.) See Container 3, Brookhaven Town Republican Committee (Box 1)
  - Alexander, Dan C. (U.S. House of Representatives, Democratic primary, Ala. First Congressional District), 1980, 1983 (Box 1)
  - American Postal Workers Union, 1979-1980 (Box 1)
  - Babylon Town Republican Committee (New York) See Container 60, Suffolk County Republican Committee (Box 1)
  - Bagnal, Anne (U.S. House of Representatives, N.C. Fifth Congressional District), 1982-1989 (Box 1)
  - Barros, Rick (U.S. House of Representatives, Mass. Tenth Congressional District), 1987 (Box 1)
  - Bean-Jones, Linda (U.S. House of Representatives, Maine First Congressional District), 1981, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Bell, Tom, 1981-1982 (Box 1)
  - Bent, Bruce See Container 55, Reserve Fund (Box 1)
  - Bernardi, Roy A. (Mayor, Syracuse, N.Y.) (Box 1)
    - Campaign packet, 1985 (Box 1)
    - Campaign positions, 1985 (Box 1)
    - Direct mail, 1985 (Box 1)
    - General, 1984-1986, (3 folders) (Box 1)
    - Mahoney, Bernie, 1985 (Box 2)
    - Media (Box 2)
      - Advertisements, 1985 (Box 2)
      - General, 1985 (Box 2)
    - News clippings, 1983-1985, (2 folders) (Box 2)
    - Planning, 1985 (Box 2)
    - Schedules, 1985 (Box 2)
    - Surveys/polls, 1984-1985, (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Blake, Harris (U.S. House of Representatives, N.C. Eight Congressional District), 1982-1984 (Box 3)
  - Blass, Gregory (U.S. House of Representatives, N.Y. First Congressional District), 1986 (Box 3)
  - Boschwitz, Rudy (U.S. Senate, Minn.), 1995-1996, 2002 (Box 3)
  - Bozwell, Brent See Container 11, Conservative Victory Committee (Box 3)
  - Bradshaw, Jim (U.S. House of Representatives, Tex. Twelfth Congressional District; Tex.Twenty-sixth Congressional District), 1980-1984, (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Brookhaven Town Republican Committee (New York) (Box 3)
    - Direct mail, 1985, (2 folders) (Box 3)
    - Election results, 1983, (2 folders) (Box 3)
    - General, 1983-1987 (Box 3)
    - General, 1988-1989 (Box 4)
    - Media, 1983-1985, (2 folders) (Box 4)
    - News clippings, 1985-1989, (2 folders) (Box 4)
    - Press releases, circa 1983 (Box 4)
    - Surveys/polls, 1985-1988, (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - Brown, Colin, 1979-1983 See also Container 42, National Citizens Coalition, (3 folders) (Box 5)
  - Brown, Hank (U.S. Senate, Colo.), 1989 (Box 5)
  - Brown, James E. (Buster) (Texas attorney general), 1985-1986 (Box 5)
  - Buckley, James Lane, (U.S. Senate, Conn.; U.S. Senate, N.Y.) See also Container 68, Buckley, James Lane (Box 5)
    - Campaign volunteer packet, 1970 (Box 5)
    - Canvassing lists, 1970 (Box 5)
    - Connecticut senate race, 1979-1981 (Box 6)
    - Dinner programs, 1970-1971 (Box 6)
    - General, 1970 (Box 6)
    - Media, 1970, (3 folders) (Box 6)
    - Media, 1970, (3 folders) (Box 7)
    - Miscellany, 1970-1971 See also Container OV 5, Scrapbook page, (2 folders) (Box 7)
    - News clippings, 1970 (Box 7)
    - Notes, 1970 (Box 7)
    - Press releases, 1970 (Box 7)
    - Surveys/polls, 1970, (4 folders) (Box 8)
  - Canfield, Roger (U.S. House of Representatives, Calif.. Fourth Congressional District), 1984 (Box 8)
  - Caputo, Bruce (U.S. Senate, N.Y.), 1979-1983, (2 folders) (Box 8)
  - Caputo, Bruce (U.S. Senate, N.Y.), 1979-1983, (2 folders) (Box 9)
  - Cantrell, Tom (U.S. House of Representatives, Okla. First Congressional District), 1983-1987, (3 folders) (Box 9)
  - Carman, Greg (U.S. House of Representatives, N.Y. Third Congressional District, 1980-1985, (3 folders) (Box 9)
  - Carrington, John (Secretary of state, N.C.), 1988 (Box 10)
  - Chiles, Eddie, 1979-1984, (5 folders) (Box 10)
  - Christian, David (U.S. House of Representatives, Penn.. Eighth Congressional District), 1984 (Box 10)
  - Cobey, William W. (U.S. House of Representatives, N.C. Fourth Congressional District), 1982-1984 For additional material see Container 43, National Congressional Club (Box 10)
  - Coleman, Marshall (Governor, Va.), 1984, 1989 (Box 10)
  - Committee to Insure Ethical Government, 1981, (2 folders) (Box 11)
  - Committee to Re-Elect the President, 1972-1973, (3 folders) (Box 11)
  - Conservative Digest, 1986 (Box 11)
  - Conservative Political Action Committee, 1984-1986 (Box 11)
  - Conservative Victory Committee, 1988 (Box 11)
  - Corcoran, Tom (Republican Primary, U.S. Senate, Ill.) See also Container 32, Koehler, Judy; Container 77, Ferdinand, Joan (Box 12)
    - Debate preparation, 1983-1984, (2 folders) (Box 12)
    - Direct mail, 1983-1984 (Box 12)
    - General, 1983-1984, (3 folders) (Box 12)
    - Media, 1983 (Box 12)
    - News clippings, 1983-1984 (Box 12)
    - Opposition research, 1977-1983 (Box 13)
    - Press releases, 1983-1984 (Box 13)
  - Crane, Philip M. (U.S. President, Republican primary) (Box 13)
    - Biography, circa 1980 (Box 13)
    - Direct mail, 1985, 1988 (Box 13)
    - Expenses and fees, 1979 (Box 13)
    - General, 1978-1979, (2 folders) (Box 13)
    - News clippings, 1978-1979 (Box 13)
    - Planning, 1978-1979 (Box 13)
    - Research notebook, 1978 (Box 14)
    - Schedules, 1978-1979 (Box 14)
    - Surveys/polls, 1978-1979 (Box 14)
  - Cunningham, Randy ("Duke") (U.S. House of Representatives, Calif. Forty-fourth Congressional District), 1990 (Box 14)
  - Curb, Michael (Lt. governor, Calif.), 1985-1986 (Box 14)
  - D'Amato, Alphonse (U.S. Senate, N.Y.) See also Container 75, D'Amato, Alphonse (Box 14)
    - Campaign planning booklet, 1984 (Box 14)
    - Direct mail, 1983-1989, (3 folders) (Box 14)
    - Election analysis, 1977, 1986, 1989, 1968 (Box 14)
    - General, 1983-1989, (5 folders) (Box 15)
    - Institute for America's Tomorrow letters, 1987 (Box 15)
    - Legislative history, 1984-1985, (2 folders) (Box 15)
    - Media (Box 16)
      - Finances, 1986-1987, (2 folders) (Box 16)
      - General, 1984-1987, (4 folders) (Box 16)
    - Miscellany, 1983-1987 (Box 16)
    - News clippings, 1980-1986 (Box 17)
    - Newsletters, 1984-1985 (Box 17)
    - Op-eds, 1985-1987 (Box 17)
    - Opposition research (Box 17)
      - Dyson, John, 1980-1986, (3 folders) (Box 17)
      - Ferraro, Geraldine, 1984-1985 (Box 17)
      - Green, Mark, 1986, (7 folders) (Box 18)
      - Holtzman, Elizabeth, 1984-1986 (Box 19)
    - Schedules, 1984-1987 (Box 19)
    - Speeches, 1985-1986 (Box 19)
    - Surveys/polls, 1984-1986 (Box 19)
  - Davis, Edward M. (State Senate, Calif.) (Box 19)
    - Crime report, 1985 (Box 19)
    - Finances, 1985, (2 folders) (Box 19)
    - General, 1980-1987 (Box 19)
    - General, 1980-1987, (2 folders) (Box 20)
    - Initiative measures, 1983 (Box 20)
    - News clippings, 1983-1987, (4 folders) (Box 20)
    - News clippings, 1983-1987 (Box 21)
    - Surveys/polls, 1985-1988, (2 folders) (Box 21)
  - Dewhurst, David (Land commissioner, Tex.), 1994-2002 (Box 21)
  - Diaz-Balart, Lincoln (U.S. House of Representatives, Fla. Eighteenth Congressional District), 1988 (Box 21)
  - Dunn, Jim (U.S. Senate, Republican primary, Mich.) (Box 21)
    - General, 1983-1986, (3 folders) (Box 21)
    - News clippings, 1982-1986, (3 folders) (Box 22)
  - Dupree, Billy Joe (U.S. House of Representatives, Tex. Twenty-fourth Congressional District), 1987 (Box 22)
  - Dusaneko, Theodore K. (County executive, Rockland County, N.Y.), 1980-1985, (2 folders) (Box 22)
  - Faircloth, Lauch (U.S. Senate, N.C.), 1998 (Box 22)
  - Fetzer, Tom (U.S. House of Representatives, N.C. Fourth Congressional District), 1987-1988 For additional material see Container 43, National Congressional Club (Box 22)
  - Fiber, Fabric and Apparel Coalition for Trade (FFACT), 1985 (Box 23)
  - Fidesz-Magyar Polgári Párt (political party: Hungary), 2013 (Box 23)
  - Fore, Rick (U.S. Senate, Nev. Republican primary) (Box 23)
    - Finances, 1981, (2 folders) (Box 23)
    - General, 1981-1989, (2 folders) (Box 23)
    - Surveys/polls, 1981-1982 (Box 23)
  - Fossel, Jon (U.S. House of Representatives, N.Y. Twentieth Congressional District), 1982-1983, (2 folders) (Box 24)
  - Foundation for Economic Research, 1987 (Box 24)
  - Gallegy, Elton (U.S. House of Representatives, Calif. Twenty-first Congressional District), 1985-1988 (Box 24)
  - Gates, Daryl (Mayor, Los Angeles, Calif.), 1988-1989 (Box 24)
  - Gilman, Benjamin (U.S. House of Representatives, N.Y. Twenty-second Congressional District), 1982-1992 (Box 24)
  - Grassley, Charles (Chuck) (U.S. House of Representatives, Iowa Third Congressional District), 1978-1981 (Box 24)
  - Gray, Lyons (U.S. House of Representatives, N.C. Fifth Congressional District), 1987-1988, (2 folders) (Box 24)
  - Guglielmo, Anthony (U.S. House of Representatives, Conn. Second Congressional District), 1981-1984 (Box 24)
  - Gusenbauer, Alfred (Chancellor, Austria), circa 2007 (Box 25)
  - Hager, Edward (Ted) (U.S. Senate, N.H. Republican primary), 1980, (2 folders) (Box 25)
  - Haggarty, Pat (U.S. House of Representatives, Tex. Sixteenth Congressional District), 1982 (Box 25)
  - Hamilton County Republicans (Ohio), 1987 (Box 25)
  - Heffernan, Roger (U.S. House of Representatives, Calif. Eighth Congressional District), 1984 (Box 25)
  - Helms, Jesse (U.S. Senate, N.C.) See also Container 43, National Congressional Club (Box 25)
    - Brochures, 1984 (Box 25)
    - Campaign case studies, 1985-1986, (2 folders) (Box 25)
    - Campaign planning, 1983 (Box 25)
    - Debate preparation, 1984 (Box 25)
    - Direct mail, 1983-1984 (Box 25)
    - Gantt, Harvey, campaign, 1990 (Box 25)
    - General, 1983-1984 (Box 25)
    - General, 1983-1984 (Box 26)
    - Jewish support, 1984 (Box 26)
    - Media, 1984 (Box 26)
    - Miscellany, 1982-1984 (Box 26)
    - News clippings, 1981-1985, (3 folders) (Box 26)
    - News clippings, 1981-1985 (Box 27)
    - Notes, 1984 (Box 27)
    - Opposition research, 1983-1984 (Box 27)
    - Social security, 1984 (Box 27)
    - Speeches, 1984 (Box 27)
    - Surveys/polls, 1983-1984, (4 folders) (Box 27)
    - Telephone canvassing proposal, 1983 (Box 28)
  - Hennesy, Dick (District attorney, Onandaga County, N.Y.), 1987 (Box 28)
  - Hermening, Kevin J. (U.S. House of Representatives, Wisc. Seventh Congressional District), 1986-1988 (Box 28)
  - Herriott, Bob (State Senate, Calif. Sixteenth District), 1985 (Box 28)
  - High Frontier, 1983-1984, (4 folders) (Box 28)
  - Houghton, Amo (U.S. House of Representatives, N.Y. Thirty-fourth Congressional District), 1986-1991 (Box 28)
  - Hrvatska demokratska zajednica (political party: Croatia), 2015 (Box 28)
  - Huff, Richard (U.S. House of Representatives, Ariz. Second Congressional District), 1980-1983 (Box 28)
  - Humphrey, Gordon J. (U.S. Senate, N.H.) (Box 29)
    - Constituent letters, 1983 (Box 29)
    - D'Amours, Norm, 1982-1984, (2 folders) (Box 29)
    - Direct mail, 1982-1984 (Box 29)
    - General, 1980-1987, (2 folders) (Box 29)
    - Media, 1984 (Box 29)
    - News clippings, 1984, (2 folders) (Box 29)
    - News clippings, 1984, (2 folders) (Box 30)
    - Surveys/polls, 1983 (Box 30)
  - Hutchinson, William A. (U.S. Senate, Ark.), 1986 (Box 30)
  - Jacob, Ted (U.S. House of Representatives, Penn. Eighteenth Congressional District), 1982 (Box 30)
  - Jepsen, Roger (U.S. Senate, Iowa), 1978-1983 (Box 30)
  - Kalikow, Peter S., 1983-1989, (2 folders) (Box 30)
  - Kalikow, Peter S., 1983-1989, (2 folders) (Box 31)
  - Kasich, John (U.S. House of Representatives, Ohio Twelfth Congressional District), 1984 (Box 31)
  - Kiernan, John (Town supervisor, North Hampstead, N.Y.), 1982, 1987 See also Container 40, Margiotta, Joseph (Box 31)
  - Kindness, Tom (U.S. House of Representatives, Ohio Eighth Congressional District) (Box 31)
    - General, 1983-1988, (2 folders) (Box 31)
    - General, 1983-1988, (2 folders) (Box 32)
    - Media, 1986, (2 folders) (Box 32)
    - News clippings, 1985-1987 (Box 32)
  - Koehler, Judy (U.S. Senate, Ill.) See also Container 12, Corcoran, Tom; Container 77, Ferdinand, Joan; For additional material see Container 45, National Conservative Political Action Committee (Box 32)
    - General, 1985-1990 (Box 32)
    - General, 1985-1990, (3 folders) (Box 33)
    - Media, 1986, (3 folders) (Box 33)
    - News clippings, 1985-1987 (Box 33)
    - News clippings, 1985-1987 (Box 34)
    - Republican Primary Survey, 1985 (Box 34)
  - Kramer, Kenneth Bentley (U.S. House of Representatives, Colo. Fifth Congressional District), 1982, 1987, (2 folders) (Box 34)
  - Lauder, Ronald S. (Governor, N.Y. Republican primary) (Box 34)
    - Contracts, 1987 (Box 34)
    - General, 1986-1990, (3 folders) (Box 34)
    - Kristallnacht Remembrance Committee, 1988 (Box 35)
    - Miscellany, 1988 (Box 35)
    - News clippings, 1987-1989, (2 folders) (Box 35)
    - Op-eds and public announcements, 1987 (Box 35)
    - Opposition research, 1987 (Box 35)
    - Surveys/polls, 1986-1989, (2 folders) (Box 35)
  - Lezar, Harold J. ("Tex") (Attorney general, Tex.), 1989 (Box 35)
  - Likud (political party: Israel), 1996-2003 See also Container 79, Israel, (8 folders) (Box 36)
  - Likud (political party: Israel), 2004-2008 (Box 37)
  - Loeb, John L., Jr. (U.S. Senate, N.Y.), 1979 (Box 37)
  - Logrande, Michael (County executive, Islip, N.Y.) See Container 61, Town of Islip Republican Committee (Box 37)
  - Long, Tom (President, Progressive Conservative Part of Ontario), 1988-1990 (Box 37)
  - Mack, Connie, III (U.S. House of Representatives, Fla. Thirteenth Congressional District; U.S. Senate, Fla.) (Box 37)
    - Announcement, 1987 (Box 37)
    - Chiles, Lawton, 1986 (Box 37)
    - Direct mail, 1985-1990 (Box 37)
    - Election results, 1982 (Box 37)
    - General, 1983-1990 (Box 37)
    - General, 1983-1990, (2 folders) (Box 38)
    - Media (Box 38)
      - Advertisements, 1982-1988 (Box 38)
      - General, 1986-1988, (2 folders) (Box 38)
    - Miscellany, 1986-1990, 2000 (Box 38)
    - Mock news conference, circa 1987 (Box 38)
    - News clippings, 1982-1984, (2 folders) (Box 38)
    - News clippings, 1985-1989 (Box 39)
    - Ryskamp, Kenneth, 1991 (Box 39)
    - Surveys/polls, 1985-1988, (2 folders) (Box 39)
    - Writings, 1982-1988 (Box 39)
  - Mackenzie, Kenneth (U.S. House of Representatives, Ind. Second Congressional District), 1981-1989, (2 folders) (Box 39)
  - Mackenzie, Kenneth (U.S. House of Representatives, Ind. Second Congressional District)), 1981-1989, (3 folders) (Box 40)
  - Malone, Joseph (U.S. Senate, Mass.; State treasurer, Mass.), 1985-1990, 1997-1998, 1988-1990 (Box 40)
  - Maltese, Serphin R. (State Senate, N.Y., Fifteenth District), 1983-1989 (Box 40)
  - Margiotta, Joseph, 1979-1993, 2004 See also Container 41, Nassau County Republican Committee, (2 folders) (Box 40)
  - Marotta, Victor (Sussex County Board of Chosen Freeholders, N.J.), 1987 (Box 41)
  - Marston, David (Governor, Penn.), 1978-1980 (Box 41)
  - Martin, Tim (U.S. House of Representatives, Ohio Thirteenth Congressional District), 1982 (Box 41)
  - Mascola, Frank (State Assembly, N.Y. Ninety-second District), 1984 (Box 41)
  - Maxwell, John See Container 55, Republican Party of Texas (Box 41)
  - McCollum, Bill (U.S. Senate, Fla.), 2000-2004 (Box 41)
  - McGrath, Raymond (U.S. House of Representatives, N.Y. Fifth Congressional District), 1984-1986 (Box 41)
  - McHoul, Doug (Legislator, Duchess County, N.Y.), 1987 (Box 41)
  - McNamera, Frank L., Jr. (U.S. House of Representatives, Mass. Eighth Congressional District), 1982-1983 (Box 41)
  - Mofaz, Shaul (Kadima party leadership, Israel), 2008 (Box 41)
  - Mondello, Joseph (U.S. House of Representatives, N.Y. Twentieth Congressional District), 1983-1984, 1991-1994 See same container, Nassau County Republican Committee (Box 41)
  - Mueller, Margaret (U.S. House of Representatives, Ohio Eleventh Congressional District), 1986-1987 (Box 41)
  - Mullin, James E. (U.S. Senate, Vt. Republican primary), 1977-1980, (2 folders) (Box 41)